oh hello hello
welcome to the comma AI office as I
promised we'd be doing a livestream at
12:00 so yeah this is the wait for a few
people to get in here III I do want to
apologize for the sunglasses I don't
think that they make me look cool
I hurt my eye so that's why I'm wearing
them and that's why I wore them in the
press you know you hurt your eye right
before press what do you do your wear
stupid look at sunglasses but uh trying
to make it work
Oh someone's at the door we have a chef
now we have I think it's the shaft am i
whispering can you hear me well I'm in
the office there's other people here
working and kind of maybe look around
all that so it's gonna be a little more
quiet than my usual periscopes but
hopefully you guys can hear me well I'm
pretty good all right I like that so
yeah we're gonna be reversing the Prius
today using Cabana I am pointing my own
camera at my monitors because I don't
know had a livestream on periscope and I
was talking to press for most of the
morning so I didn't have time to look
into YouTube streaming um there's
something else we're also gonna be doing
on this livestream so let's switch over
to the other camera
so here is cabana and over here is the
number of pandas we've sold 336 pandas
now I wish that map was actually where
the pandas went to but that was kind of
hard to do so that's actually the map of
the shipper users for the last 24 hours
but yeah here we are pointed at cabana
can i zoom out no I can't
hey Peter bench so I have my phone on a
mount I'm using a mount like the same
ones we use for Scheffer maybe I can yes
Kawika van up yeah I need viv back to
hold the camera yo st. bad this'll work
um so everybody check it out if you
haven't seen it here is a comma AI panda
the production pandas will look even
better than this this is a remedy panda
all pandas that are going to be sold
will be red sea pandas are FC pandas
function as phone fast chargers as they
have to GM lands they can plug into your
computer without an extra cable and we
got another Panda sale that's 337 pandas
keep it coming keep on buying pandas and
I will show you some of the stuff that
you can do with a panda and this tool
we've created called Cabana so if you
guys tuned in to my other livestream not
my most recent one where I streamed open
pilot go on a Best Buy
I used the this stuff on the Toyota
Prius so let me just move here to when
we're actually driving I'm so this is my
driving video this was actually captured
with a neo but it looked exactly the
same if you capture with Schiffer
probably even looks better because
phones are better at knitting the camera
Neos are Neos are needed for machine
learning phones I need it to make
good-looking pictures so let's wait for
this to load up here there's a lot of
load on our servers today you know a lot
of people are getting into Khmer I for
the first time I'm so I've already found
a few simple things you can see this is
like the wheel speed plot oh no no
that's not buggy I get gold just loading
yeah those lines on the graph are a
little annoying we'll have to we'll have
to check them out that's perfectly
synced up with where I'm clicking it
should be let me just refresh this page
here you'll see what we get twe hundred
and thirty-eight pandas so I'm also on
Twitter I'm looking at the news and I'm
looking on slack I will also try to look
at this periscope screen so um what
we're seeing here is the video from my
Prius Drive correlated with the messages
that were actually on the Prius canvas
at the same time okay we can we can we
can go to landscape mode let's let's see
what we can do here these phone mounts
this isn't really how phones are meant
to be used I don't think this does this
that I think the the portrait was better
um an update to do what so we will
probably release a firmware update in
the next week that starts to add some of
the so all of the software functionality
like the elm327 emulation mode and the
windows support and the linux driver
support that's all gonna work on Revie
as well support more car as well if you
want to support more cars oh oh the
support more cars with the pandas yeah
so yeah I mean some cars don't expose
that much on the OBD port and will be
constrained to getting sort of the same
things that the typical dongles get
because the manufacturers just didn't
put the data there now you can get
around this by wiring the Panda
correctly into the canvas of your car
it's it's less hard to do than it sounds
and okay here we are so this is a plot
of the wheel speed and the Prius now
let's see what we can find here so I
think this signal is the brake see if
that's true this is the brake amount now
on a Prius you have two kinds of brake
you have the regen bike and you have the
physical brake now I don't like when I'm
clicking here how it's jumping to the
next thing I thought this bug was fixed
let's try refreshing again and see what
we get and we are up to three hundred
and forty one pandas 'im one of the
really cool things about this whole
ecosystem is you're not constrained to
use like when you log the data
it literally logs all of the data from
your car
it doesn't just log what we understand
now so when you log it you can look in
the future if somebody figures out where
a signal is on a car you'll be able to
get access to information on all your
pasture outs as well all right now it
looks fixed looks fixed until I scroll
this
also yeah we need to stand up a bit more
so the demo link has been posted all the
articles and literally we're getting you
know hundreds of hits per minute to this
interface so that's why everything's a
little bit laggy and slow okay so now
you see what's happening when I click
there it's jumping clicks here and then
it jumps let's see if we can uh let's
see if we can go on slack here and get
Andy over here to take a look and
speculate at what might be happening so
this app is written in react it's really
easy to go in and push changes out
seeing a cabana bug on the live stream
yeah so these these these lines are here
which has something to do with it at
times not being synced correctly hey
welcome to the welcome to the
livestreams everybody want to welcome my
aunty
so Andrew here is the one who wrote
cabana and I'll show you the bug mercy
so when I click
here it jumps
I mean I'm cooking here and it's I
thought we fixed this I'm also still
seeing the lines in the graph it doesn't
seem to happen on the first Prius
segment it seems to only happen when I
scroll to the next for your segments we
play a live internal version so I can
use the live internal version on the
periscope and then once we do all these
bug fixes we'll push it out Devon so
yeah this is why this is why we have
teams of people working to make this
stuff stable and great let's go over
here and look at our pan anniversary so
344 keep become more pandas more pandas
more pandas so some of the things we
want to look for in order to make the
Prius supported by open pilot is how the
Prius is actually controlling the brakes
and the steering so this brake packet
here looks to be the actual brake that
the car is doing but it's not
necessarily the command that you send to
the car in order to trigger a braking
event so for that what we have to do is
we'll find in the video so if you guys
remember everybody saw me do this Drive
we can find where the the ACC hit the
brakes
probably this thing yeah right so you
can see that I'm coming to a stop there
see how it's out of sync right now
that's the bug we gotta fix it should be
much better in sync and then what you're
seeing right now if we go over the demo
route could show you how long
we think it is so actually anybody can
go to this URL community.com AI slash
Cabana question mark demo equals one so
this is the demo route from the acura
you'll see on this one when I pull out
the steering angle when I go unlike to
the powertrain data I plot the
transmission speed you'll see it sync up
really well so you see when I click on
this here we're gonna see the car
decelerate at the stop sign you can see
how that's correlated right there we'll
come to it was that not a complete stop
that graph did not touch the access
fortunately the police don't have api's
so we can't report you to the police so
we'd never do anything like that because
we're not terrible people but yeah you
can see coming in first stop and it's
cool we can actually use speed profiles
that look like this in the machine
learning to determine where stop signs
are without having to use any visual
features at all to determine the stop
sign so yeah I mean you expect this here
to be a turn you can see it's a turn
that's the steering angle so we have a
lot of stuff already figured out on the
Acura but there's a few things that we
don't have figured out so there's these
like xxx 4 packet so if you look at this
packet you'll notice that there are no
signals labeled for it this one always
seems to have that value let's highlight
it and create a signal let's plot it and
see if it ever changes nope it looks
very boring maybe there's nothing
interesting on xxx for about xxx one
it's pretty boring as well so you can
kind of see how interesting a packets
gonna be by looking at how red it is
over here in the signal explorer red
means that it's changing so if we look
at these ones down here these are
actually packets from the radar so
they're not filled in on this DBC
because this is the accurate DBC and not
the radar did you say but if I go here
and I plot this signal you'll see that
it's going to correspond to how close
so I am to the car in front of me so let
me just zoom in here and you'll see if
you can see in the video you can see
that car off in the distance there you
can see that we're getting closer to it
I'm sure there's even much better
examples of that yes that's the first
radar the first radar thing usually ends
up being the lead and this route is
available to everybody so you guys can
actually play along with me at home um
so let's say we coming up on a car here
let's move this over and let's see if
that works on the demo route
hmm I'm seeing the same sync issues on
the demo route that I was seeing with
the other route so I just have to wait -
let's fix so there's so much can data on
your car that it's hard to load it into
the memory of the web browser all at
once so that's why we have this slider
here which lets you select the portion
of your route that you're currently
working with needs to only work right
now on the first portion of the route
I'm sure that I'll be fixed up soon
let's see I didn't email so they should
be sure we have public email or
everything else very interesting they're
probably not interesting I usually get
emails for people who want to and I
quote like collaborate on ideas and I'm
like okay so what's the idea I tell them
to be concrete sure if they know what
concrete means because I very rarely get
like a concrete proposal like I want
this or we have this or let's make these
two systems work together it's more like
let's meet for coffee and chat and you
know I would drink way too much coffee
if I took everybody up on those offers
and that wouldn't work I mean any any
sorta and it like VCS complain about
this all the time - it like come to me
with like a real pitch let's check out
the panel's it's a panda huh okay
someone sent me a email with the subject
batteries I think it's interesting do I
know anything about batteries let me
read the email we'll see if it's
interesting while we wait for Andy to
fix that bug we can also check out how
many pandas we've sold how many pandas
you guys think result being sold 350
pandas this is it's pretty exciting it's
a few more than we expected to sell 420
420 would be nice I mean let's let's
let's keep it rolling so if we do manage
to hit 5,000 over the next month we're
gonna give all the early people the
option of a 3d printed case or an
injection-molded case and people after
that we'll all get injection molded
cases I think the 3d printed case looks
pretty nice but the injection molded
case might look a little bit more
professional yeah you know our main goal
for forgetting pandas out there is to
have people start reverse engineering
all the cars in the world let's look at
what sensors are on these cars let's
look at how to control these cars and we
thought about offering the Panda Ultra
Edition which is a Black Panther and the
Panda in a black case and that would be
one hundred eighty eight dollars does it
get you anything better no it doesn't
but it would be one hundred eighty eight
dollars it would be a panda in a black
case if anyone wants to buy one of those
email me I'll sell to you personally
when will drive sharing be available in
Cabana yeah we should work on drive
sharing so right now they're share
features built into shipper but I think
they're limited to like gifts and videos
and small pictures someday someday for
now you just have to let someone log
into your account but um I mean you can
also do it with with api's you can also
do it with the with the ship or API if
you grant if somebody writes an app they
can grant API access using the
shipwright api and that's all on our
github what's the difference to clab car
I don't know what a clap car is on
Twitter here this is somebody I should
show you guys the Twitter when I mean in
with Twitter okay can I just do that
here there we go
what is the difference to cloud car
let's see what a cloud car is I should
cause my email to have secrets and that
doesn't receive it fits Google News
that's my slack with Andy if I fix it
months
LabCorp well that's expensive 99 euros
see so my problem with all these are
their dongles is that they don't tell
you what it's an L like like the elves
do not let you read all of the data off
of the canvas they also don't tell you
what port oh wow oh wow we just sold
five more pandas they don't tell you
what actual our connections there are on
the on the obd-ii port obedia and we say
ODB it sounds better but it's not it's
obd so we actually show you exactly
what's exposed on our dongle right here
so we show that we have the three cam
buses to LAN or Kaline buses and then
1gm land oh and that's like what it you
know the actual electrical Hardware
interface is this pin is another ground
they're tied together on production
pandas this pin is not really used it's
used on some cars as like a special
clear mode but our panel doesn't connect
anything to that and this interface we
call the J shade interface no modern
cars really have it so we just we just
don't made it at it was it was extra
worthless hardware this is what really
lets you get access to light so every
one of these canvases plus the GM LAN is
on like the Chevy Volt in the Chevy Volt
for example so we want to make sure you
can get access to really all this stuff
about your car like can three on the on
the on the vault is just a battery can
it talks about the status of each
battery in the Prius in the in the vault
the Prius only has the amount of two
kids I don't know but we wired in the
Prius we actually wired the Panda in two
I love Twitter we wired the Panda into
the
the same place that the stock camera
system connects to so if you watch that
video I'm going back to my driving
explorer here and maybe things will
start working these are my drives of the
Prius let's put this one here
what's up from India 357 penis 357
slowly Perlas oh I remember what I did I
had hit that window let's go back here
don't open to many cabanas it is a
pretty intensive web app which vehicles
are we most interested in next the more
people have the vehicle the more
interested we are in it newer vehicles
have more sensors but yeah so let's
let's sex out of this one here and let's
go back to this this pretty strap here
yeah it doesn't it just seemed to be a
problem only with this when I select
things that are not the first andis type
unless you guys decide
can't repro with the Prius rap I recode
with a demo Wow yeah
maybe I'll wait doesn't seem to always
do it so maybe I have to wait for the
first part to finish loading let's try
that so let's just refresh here we'll
wait for the first part to fully load in
this might be a problem with just
zeroing your time then also check out
where our shifty users are on this map
here so we have a lot of our ship users
in America someone down there and the
Dominican Republic and this is just
for users in the last 24 hours
scattered all over Europe
yeah Southeast Asia
either look over there cool so let me
scroll this now and see if it doesn't
happen
oh yeah
the wines are gone but the junkies are
no reverse-engineering is a slow slow
process happening even after season yeah
when I click here it shouldn't like jump
there like that maybe this is it's not
even sync to operate so if you see like
when I click here that's actually at the
peak speed of the car it just looks like
the line is in the wrong place
yeah I think we can make this work for
versatility right but we really want
these tools to be a a wonderful
experience to use as a program that I
used for a lot of binary reverse
engineering called Ida and it really is
it's a wonderful program to use and you
can just spend hours exploring all the
stuff that's in a it's in a binary
so yes you click here it does that click
here so yeah wherever I click is where
it's actually going so you can make that
work that looks like where I changed
lanes and we get affirm that by turning
on the steering angle plot
oh snap
365 pandas I do promise that these bugs
will be fixed long long before you get
your panda they'll even be fixed tonight
because I want to start dating in and
reverse engineering the Prius I bought I
bought some cool stuff for the Prius
about this thing here is a USB monitor
so we're not gonna put the big touch
panel in the Prius we're just gonna put
this guy in there I also have a gaming
PC coming in the mail today anylock yeah
alright I'll show you what I'm doing
maybe I'm maybe I'm clicking wrong with
this let me put this monitor away it
comes with like a little carrying case -
it's cute
what Asus thing
so I love it Prius route you're very
fresh um so I can't even wait it still
happens
so now that I'm loaded I drag this over
to here I mean a lot of times
bugs are caused by people clicking wrong
yeah 368 pandas um if you have a panda
can others go through the data so know
if you have a panda that data we don't
share your data with anybody um we could
people are asking a lot for that feature
if they want to be able to share their
routes tribest make it happen okay cool
so now it's just just being slow no well
know sometimes people click wrong you
know I mean sometimes it's broken but
sometimes people click crop Faculty's
fast
oh come on crowd
and he disappears when the bug happens
he's not here we go
save your GBC progress I did I already
saved it come in today github so if you
see cabana integrates with the open DBC
project 370 pandas um cabana integrates
with the opened DBC project so I can
load my DB C's here and I can fork it to
my own github so then if I want to save
my progress I can just go to save DBC
and notice how its forked to geo hot
open DBC I can just click commit to
github and now it's shared on my github
okay
so Andy sent me a link to an internal
build of Cabana so fast will make the
real one faster we'll stand by our
caching server in front of the web page
so let me just log in to this can I log
into this with github is that gonna work
no oh
because it won't redirect me the right
URL okay okay so no DBC but let's see if
the bugs that I could save to a text
file so you don't have to save your DBC
is to open DV city you can save them to
text files so I like scroll to here
speed now you know where that would be
I just called my get up here go to my
personal gate on github geo hot open BBC
there we can look in these DBC file so
DBC is kind of the industry standard
file for car or specifications a shale
is sensors are in your car so these are
the wheel sensors for my car so you can
see their own packet 170 which i think
is a a and hex what's not doing it now
oh you made a change
oh you made all you fix the bug alright
alright alright well the uh oh this is
this is exciting
um and yeah I mean I think we'll leave
it up for today but I think we'll make
this go away on the other production
ones okay cool the way the bug is fixed
thank you all right all right it's fixed
um so yeah we'll get that we'll get that
out what's great about it being a web
app you're we're on the periscope you
want to join it you want to say hi to
the periscope
periscope can they can they hear you I
don't know hey yeah Cabana Cabana is a
web app yeah wow that's true that we had
an internal betting pool for how many
pandas we were gonna sell and if you bet
on a lot of pant as you want
a cow that we have bug-free open DBC
that bug-free you'll always be bugs bugs
are bugs are on going forever struggle
um so yeah you just paste your DBC in
here so it's gonna raw select all copy
you go here paste continue editing from
paste oh I see very high quality okay
cool so now we have those signals we
were working with before and look look
look the lines are gone and now when I
click on the graph notice how it
actually goes to the correct place so
let's try to find where where the
breaking is happening so the car had the
adaptive cruise control on I believe at
this point you guys probably watch this
video how does a t-mobile sync up differ
from a t-mobile sync up drive device do
you think t-mobile would ever make an
interface that looks like this I'm sure
the t-mobile Drive device tells you how
many miles you drove maybe so much I
sure but it's so much from a screenshot
of that so how does it differ it gives
you a whole lot more access to your car
than any other reasonably priced dongle
that had come before in the past if you
wanted this kind of access you were
buying things from companies like
cabassa
for for $2000 this competes with really
the dongles that the manufacturers use
not the consumer grade ones ok cool so
let's assume that this braking event
here so you can see it's a braking event
because we lose a lot of speed quickly
let's assume that this braking event
here was caused by the ACC being
triggered right so I have down here a
new message one one of these is ah here
we go see that this one here track is
zero is the so these you can see that
some of these are zeros and some of
these are ones zeros are on the first
canvas and ones are on the second canvas
so I can go down here to this track is
zero one and I can plot the longitudinal
distance to the car in front of me and
this makes a lot of sense you'll see
that as I approach the car
well I think actually the target changes
there so I think here this is a packet
from the radar in the Prius so you can
see that here it's tracking this car
over on the left and then once that car
leaves like the cone of influence it
switches over to this car and you can
see that kind of parabolic parabolic
braking this by the way is not how you
want to really do it this was kind of an
uncomfortable braking event I talked
about this during the last livestream
but but a limo driver school they tell
you be hard on the brakes at first and
then soften up as time goes on okay so
we have our wheel speed we have our
longitudinal distance let's take a look
here at the brake package so to confirm
that this actually is the brake pedal I
would expect oh it's not really the
brake pedal because I didn't press the
brake pedal this was done automatically
by the cruise control so I think we
should rename this to something that
makes more sense maybe this one will
call brake Bri J you know when you're
reverse engineering you just take a lot
of guesses at names and then you make it
better and better over time and this is
gonna be an ongoing project and we'll
call this one brake mount you can see
this is all reactive that version is
deployed live now cool the bug is
already fixed for everybody that was
that was quick let's say thank you Andy
on slack what do you say thanks because
it'd be stupid if I said thank you Andy
on the slack Channel that's a DM Jam
let's check the Twitter I love Twitter
cool okay so back to finding the break
packet so it's possible that one of
these things was actually the trigger
for the break though doubtful I'm one
way we could test this as we could find
another place in the route that I know I
braked without using the adaptive cruise
control for now let's just unplug these
and I know that it's not gonna be on the
radar can so I can use this filter here
how am I going to say 0 : is the filter
so it has to be one of these packets
let's see if we can find one that
changes right yeah
how's kind of tempting this new message
one over here and this signal here let's
try plotting that seeing what we get
okay well there's a lot of a lot of
bouncing around zero that's probably
because it's actually a it's signed
maybe it's signed 102 zero just has a
special meaning interesting I wonder I
don't know what that signal is doesn't
have any ideas don't think it's the
signal that actually triggers the break
though I might have also kind of lined
it up long so let me try going there
okay so that looks a whole lot more
sensible notice how this graph really
improved a lot um this looks more like
to me is probably something like an
accelerometer right so this is Excel or
on excel um and then when you are
talking in a car frame of a car the car
travels forward in the X direction and
then Y is to the left so I'm gonna call
this excel X so I missed that question
haven't been good at keeping up with the
periscope because the things a little
bit behind what my eyes are looking when
I'm on the screen yes and that looks
like that just looks like an
accelerometer you know what this one's
probably Excel Y to Y value so we can
actually confirm if that's correct so
that's a lot of noise I don't look at
how small the numbers are but we can
confirm if that's correct by plotting it
with the steering angle and finding a
place in the segment where we actually
steer the car so that's Excel ax so
that's breaking of the car but do we
have a place where we steer here was
first year still a lot and you reduced
you a lot okay maybe that's not Excel
why
maybe that's Excel Z what was another
thing in there but yeah it could just be
like acceleration in the Z direction but
that's a whole lot harder to test so
let's shift record the phone
accelerometer it does um we should make
it so you can graph that as well that
would be a good idea we can then just
correspond them you know very simply
I spell that right these Google things
to see if I spelled it right - I spent -
right okay but that's not we're looking
for we are looking for the brakes so
let's just remove that signal there or
get on plot hold this and let's go back
to our good breaking event so this is
our good braking event here so the radar
is gone let's so you can go a little bit
before the braking events let's see if
we can figure out what changes look over
here
figure out what changes in order to
trigger that these packets look like
they become active but that might just
be the speed over here no it's not it's
not I always plot bad and you can tell
it it's assigned value so let's um let's
make it signed
[Music]
hmm okay that looks like something maybe
this is the signal that controls the
brakes a good kind of way that I found
to do this was let's look at what else
is in this same packet maybe we can
guess so another thing that we're gonna
have soon as well is live cabana mode um
so you're not going to need to upload
your route to shiver wait and then
process it in the past you'll be able to
do this all locally in real time we're
gonna write some JavaScript code using
web USB which will just let you plug
your panda into your computer go to
cabanaconde i and then run it right
there kind of like if you guys have used
like my ether wallet you know it's a
JavaScript based if you're in wallet but
it can talk to your physical like
cryptocurrency like just ledger so it's
the same kind of thing okay so these
signals might be something to do with
the brakes they're kind of interesting
oh well okay so the thing that we're
gonna have to check and compare it to is
other places where the brakes are used
we want to find the one where it was
autonomous on the brakes and I don't
think it's this because this just looks
like it correlates with that looks like
it correlates with the acceleration
there right like so yeah I don't really
know what this signal is just offhand
but it's not what we're looking for I
can tell you that
it's are tempting because they're quiet
and then they come alive that stuff when
the breaking happens yes panda can read
and write to the canvas but when it's
used with shiver it's only it's only
using a rebuilding mode shiver doesn't
write to your canvas but if you're using
it in like most like Linux socket can or
using it with something like open pilot
yeah that's gonna write to your canvas
you know there's a certain amount of
caution to exercise what you're writing
but it's it's not it's not like you're
gonna mess something up probably the
first time you do it do urge you to be
careful but at least when it's in
read-only mode you know that you cannot
mess anything up is a 2011 Acura TSX
compatible with Panda to take control of
the gas steering in breaks I don't know
I don't have that time but if you watch
what we do for the Prius you can use the
same procedure to determine if you can
if your car has adaptive cruise control
and Lane keep assist like if you've seen
the car hit the brakes or move the
steering wheel then there's a good bet
that you'll be able to do with Panda um
if you've never seen the car move the
steering wheel by itself then they
probably can't
all right so let's focus on what we're
doing all the Twitter notifications are
so tempting I love Twitter
so you see what I'm looking for here I'm
looking for a signal that's gonna light
up right when that breaking event starts
so now there are there are worse
possibilities it is remotely possible so
these signals you notice they have a lot
less frequency than these signals and
this is the count that happened in the
three minute chunk that I'm currently
looking at so it's probably one of these
more frequent signals than breaks
usually update pretty fast yeah so the
common neo the board that's in the
common neo is kind of like a rev one of
the Panda I'm finding gas break events
is actually really easy you can get
finding the speed on a car it's just
usually you know trivial you can just
spot it because it's Carlino with the
video but yeah we should be plotting we
can get GPS speed we got accelerometer
and we can put all that data in the same
format that you see here and you'll be
able to graph it coming soon to cabana
yes so and you know actually if you have
a neo right now you can go on the day I
think Explorer and you can use Cabana
and you can do what I'm doing right here
come on your own drives panda is kind of
just like the v2 of that hardware if you
put your car into a lower gear the brake
does push in automatically you're
talking about like like engine braking
or actual like braking so even if the
car can't move the steering wheel or
brakes there's a possibility you'll be
able to control it but it gets it gets
tricky and fancy at that point you might
need to like change the firmware that's
running on your car it is it is doable
but um you know be careful
this is the break it's it's kind of nice
that the break that the computerized
brake shows up on the same graph as the
human brake on the Honda this isn't the
case then it just doesn't break hold for
you that's pretty smooth pretty cold
let's confirm that that's actually the
brake all the time even when I'm using
it
yeah the ACC was not driving there I was
driving there so that is a human brake
event and it's on the same axis I'm
gonna break hold see that you see that
see that linear see that linear up right
there that feels super uncomfortable you
want to brake hard in the beginning
which it did but then it looked like
whatever its controller was wasn't well
calibrated and had this linear op not to
be fair that's after the car looks stops
so maybe it maybe it's this because I
remember the brake event feeling really
uncomfortable
oh okay so I'm not actually on the
remote one I'm on Andy's local one and
do you erase my DBC and said you
refreshed it yeah also ejected the rila
no eyes I didn't have anything really
figured out anyway that was the leader
was not at the driving school so let's
go in here to route we were looking at
and let's see if that bug fix actually
did go live well so that doesn't
actually happen on the real one that's
just cuz it's in our reaction debugging
mode oh man it feels slow on the server
big proxy gonna put a big proxy
yes yeah of course you can talk it with
iPhone on the App Store shiver Panda iOS
support went out this morning or maybe
yesterday we tried to get it expedited
to Apple but
Apple didn't expedite it for us yeah
that will that will go out soon Andy the
bugs still there did I not refresh well
I spammed refresh a lot that's a good
idea say oh yeah no it's it's coming iOS
soon let me tell you pad stop
oh it's fixed yeah I just found
refreshed oh no no no it's still
happening how do I force for control was
a reload the cache does this disable
writing to the cache for only reading
from the cache
I miss Cassius they make things fast
it's broken charlie yeah why are you so
sure about that I disabled cash okay
inspect right click on refresh Oh hard
reload oh look at that look at that look
at these people come and go do it is
that kind of do it though I don't I
don't feel like it's the same show you
deployed
can we put out a little version my
Cabana no I see in the bog let's check
it out while we wait I love Twitter
make sure we actually this is this was
that one today right how does it look
you bought a panda - I think it'll work
on Mazdas maybe
reverse engineering requires a lot of
patience
well we will stick a a version on cabana
so you'll be able to know when which
which which version you are or 10 to 20
employees that's true should we update
our CrunchBase I don't know how to do
that can we do that do you guys do that
know how it works
we're gonna get to we're gonna get to
400 pandas probably on this stream and
then we'll do the Panda telephone thing
where we all chant ill we get to 404 you
guys can buy a panda and watch a number
go up on the livestream chopin to
counter so we are at 377 right now maybe
I'll just leave the livestream running
point it at the Panda counter so you
guys can buy pandas and watch it go up
by app and watch it go up can we also
depend affirm reverse monk shivers yeah
we're gonna get better about the
shippers Panda firmware management I
think you like 30 pandas um oh by the
way if anyone is watching who's
interested we have some bulk pricing for
pandas too if you want to be a panda
resell air yeah we did have we did have
someone come in and buy it by 10 pandas
last minute will the price increase yeah
maybe I don't know say no I think it'll
be it for a while we might be it might
be 88 for the pre-orders and then 99 we
put it on amazon coupon code pandas yeah
I think I think we will send out maybe
we could send coupon codes do people
have a lot of californica that's a good
idea yeah already 30km sales are doing
we're doing quite well I'm happy with
how many we sold so our hope was to sell
a thousand over the month but this rate
even with this is this is doubling my
projections so I think we'll end up
selling 2011 there's some chance we'll
get to 5,000 we're gonna be doing some
live streams are gonna be showing off
more and more panda features as they
come in what's the margin on
Panda less hi than you might think
especially at this scale we are making
some amount of money but you know it's
more about about getting this getting
really high quality car interface
hardware out there because everything
will do in the future depends on it you
know this is the standard VC model kind
of stuff right yeah okay are we fixed or
can I use the other one and not have it
refresh on me no he's gone right click
Oh empty cache and hard reload wow that
sounds even better
deployed version works in your machine
no no no no so I found a new button that
might have actually fixed that I found
the right click and empty cache and a
hard reload button
yeah it's fixed yeah Chrome loves
caching typical developer andis great
man we wouldn't have we wouldn't have
these great tools no man if you guys
can't revote I don't know it's working
now it's better now so we know the empty
cache and refresh buttons which is
pretty cool right 377 are we gonna get
to 400 we get to 400 pandas works for me
won't fix it's got to work for me you
know how things work around here
all right so let's go back to where we
were we labeled that accelerometer but
it's gone we'll never see that again now
I remember what it was as we can add in
those signals real fast again so if you
remember they were sine signals are you
designer too you should be able to not
have to click like edit and save you
should be able to just don't click on
these things so I'm gonna call this one
Excel Z all well I can't press ENTER to
save all right we're gonna order to make
that work it is going to get much better
but actually if you use the actual tools
that cost a lot of money to do this oh
they're they're way worse and cabaa of
course is free for people who have
pandas or Neos you don't even have to
give us any money to use cabana you
could just build Neil you know just
camera to landscape um I tried that and
it didn't work well it was it was it was
just
pointing the results were disappointing
because our Cabana probably not is
falling not maybe he'll think about it
look better on your screens when I when
I rotate please do it is it is it is a
reactor well think about we don't want
dongle makers taking our great software
and putting it in crappy dongles all
right all right landscape but you guys
really want that landscape ions Geoff
I'm gonna stand this up maybe this will
work no no that did not work oh you know
what I think what'll work is if we spin
this around so I'm just using a mount
like one of the chipper mounts from my
phone you can actually read the words
okay
okay what's gonna make this work its
first we go like this then if you don't
like my keyboard hey that's an expensive
keyboard man cost more than a panda
alright landscape is upside down and
only looking at the keyboard is that
better guys yeah okay that's chai okay
this this isn't working
you know this is why I'll never be a
YouTube celebrity because I'm not good
at pointing cameras of things I could
make it on YouTube oh okay oh you know
what we have oh I know what we have
oh this is a good amount to system I
audio tool which you can buy from our
shipper page and we get with all money
so it's a good deal um cool I should get
a head mount ya know and I'm killing you
I know I know all right
is that better don't know how these
hearts work something you guys are happy
with what I'm doing my audio is what I
have in my STI yeah it's pretty good
maybe we can even even edit this to put
the Panda number down here
so we can put that Panda sales right
save alright 377 pandas and now I'm
feeling I'm feeling a little off alright
alright it's better alright cool I'm
glad you guys like it
alright so let's go back to finding
signals the bugs are fixed everything
takes time you know that's something
that's something you learn starting a
company you think you're gonna you think
you can I saw self-driving cars in a
year know some part of my brain maybe
thought that but the truth is everything
takes a long time shipping is free
shipping is for you anywhere in the
world mostly because I didn't want to
have to deal with charging for shipping
so you know if you're in the u.s. you
are amortizing the shipping costs for
those in Indian Switzerland and stuff
but you know hey again it's really just
about getting the hardware out there I
mean about about these I always say like
like people are asking me about Baidu
and help I do stole are the Android of
self-driving cars line like yeah I mean
that's what you know they but the
dinner-hour competition the battle is
between open and closed so yeah you know
the more of these we get out there the
more open hopefully cars will become
okay
so let's rename this message also had
auto population of the size of these
messages cuz actually think this might
be a shorter message I mean we know how
big the messages are on the bus yeah
most of this is just trial and error
just kind of guessing and drawing plots
and being like hmm
does that look right like I don't know I
don't know what this is so let's just
draw a graph of it and let's say it's
very noisy well that's probably because
these aren't all the same signal or
maybe just is that noisy oh no there's
other things you can tweak too like the
nd in this so actually we have it if you
drag it like this it's little-endian and
then you drag it the other way it's big
endian you can also change that nd in
this right here but let's remove those
signals those don't look like anything
good so yeah I mean things just a lot of
fun to play with you can sit here and
just look through all the signals in
your car and take good guesses of what
they might be but we are on a mission to
find how the cards the break so there is
some chance that it actually isn't on
here and it's hidden in some other bus
of the car we didn't log all the buses
in the car so I'm gonna have to get to
with by sending the right sort of
commands to bypass gateways now one of
the interesting things that panda is
going to offer is being able to be used
with these these up I don't think this
is refreshing being able to be used with
these windows tools that you can get
from the manufacturer so you can go to
Honda tech infocomm you can go to Toyota
tech info and you can find all of the
these manufacturer tools which let you
act as your car in there they're mostly
for mechanics but um they'll be able to
actually use those with pandas and not
have to buy the $1500 Bosch interface
which is pretty cool I'll put that
filter back on 379 come on let's get the
400 guys we can do a Florida baos at
some point let's chat as a subject of an
email 1200 by Monday that would be nice
I got distracted by email what was what
was your question say it again I'll
answer
what is the best that's kind of
interesting
so please like signals on a car what are
they yeah the bbc's that you create in
cabana can definitely be used by open
pilot actually if you go to the open
pilot really file you'll find that it's
actually using this open DBC project
here an open DBC is the same project
that Cabana interfaces with when you go
to load DBC and save DBC so these can
directly be used in open pilot if you
find the right messages 3:81 come on
let's keep it going four hundred four
hundred pandas what do they do on
telephones is the Panda eventually gonna
replace the Neo well the Panda can't
replace the Neo um the Neo is a hardware
that runs our self-driving software but
there is a board inside of the Neo and
yeah I mean you can already replace that
board with a panda we have this board
called the giant panda it's in the Neo
repository our automakers gonna encrypt
the can bus I get this question all the
time okay look Apple tried for years to
stop jailbreaking they eventually
succeeded but it took them almost 10
years and that's Apple do you really
think there's any way the automakers can
keep me out by the way you offer your
the right to do this stuff - there's a
bunch of bills in Congress like right to
repair a DMCA on cars I mean you know if
you're if you're adding functionality or
you're repairing functionality on your
car it's well within your rights we will
be at 600 by tomorrow morning I could
see that I could see that yeah we take
it would take them something in ten
years if it's even sort of possible I
mean can you know a can message is only
eight bytes or this is think old can FD
which can do more bytes but that's
that's a long way away - right
pressing on the brakes where are we
pressing on the brakes this one looks
like it's changing but it's changing
slowly this is something but it doesn't
look like the brakes that signals kind
of interesting
ah this could be the signal watch
so what this could be is kind of a no no
no no no no this looks more like maybe
what's happening with the suspension of
the car maybe the tilt angle of the car
right as you think about how the car is
gonna come tilt audio will help you log
things uh yeah I mean it will probably
will probably add that to neo and
Scheffer at some point it'll be very
much opt-in audio and front cameras are
very sensitive stuff we're never gonna
log those by default but ya know I mean
it would be a helpful tool to reverse
engineer if you could record the audio
as well 384 guys alright so I don't know
what this is either but it's like
fascinating signals in this car probably
not that one
so maybe we'll just name this one tilt
maybe
cabana opensource uh we'll see we'll
think about it
maybe the land oh you mean like the
derivative I shouldn't call this tilt
maybe I should call it something
better than that
those things just seen all over the
place too
I mean they might be part of it maybe
this is just a super big signal
does this work with 32-bit signals maybe
it doesn't work with 32-bit signals okay
all right well that's the list of bugs
we shouldn't call it till maybe
I'll call it just been that is not
how you sell suspension that's why to be
a pooh-bah thanks google sauce pen oh it
is hazel suspension
we not what we're looking for
spoons are active a halt
okay look at this packet this packet
starts to do stuff once the breaking
starts so you see it's nothing
oh okay I think we're onto something
notice how it's nothing glitches a
little there and then there we go now it
starts breaking okay and that looks like
it's going down with the yeah dude is
this the one we found before let's make
that that's clearly signed so is that is
that the brake actuation command
so this makes sense breaking Forsman
break is fairly linear with maybe not
check out this one
now imagine doing all of this stuff
without cabana
it was super tedious and annoying like
every one of those things that I'm doing
now with a couple mouse clicks would
take you know you'd have to plot that in
Python you'd have to write Python code
in a notebook
hello I'm watching you you have to plot
that in a notebook and it would take a
lot of time all right so this definitely
has to do with the breaks
I think this last thing here is some
sort of checksum but I don't really know
how it works
just call Jackson
I know the Honda checksums work so one
thing I actually like about this car
less than the Honda is the Honda doesn't
just have a check so it has a counter
and counters are really cool to make
sure that your interface is not
replaying stale data um this car doesn't
look like it has that so you can
actually go in here if you want like
expand one message you can expand it you
can see what the actual values of these
are at anytime I can throw those on the
plot real quick close that off at play
okay so that definitely has to do with
the brakes so the way these messages
work is they usually come from one of
the one of the modules of the car so
there's a chance this is a great command
and this is break actual ah
so now let's zoom out and see if there's
any way that's correct because we should
not see that wherever we know we see it
here - it's very clean now wait again
this is where I was before
how does this go up when the car
accelerates oh I might be really dumb
you know with this no but how come it
totally drops out there this stuff
almost looks like it could be like rpm
or something see what makes this car
extra tricky is the fact that it's a
hybrid
I've never reverse engineered a hybrid
before so this has a gas motor and an
electric motor I'm doing doing different
things let's see all right well those
are not what we're looking for
387 let's get to 400 you guys
you know the hybrid nests of this car
makes it kind of tricky get better about
this you know maybe I just need to read
up more on hybrids um you know what
let's do a little reading um so one of
the ways that I've found to learn things
about cars is you can go sign up on tech
info Toyota comm a secret password check
slack
yeah maybe the best way to talk to me is
on slack because I can actually look
over at that at that monitor would this
help you oh oh I forgot about this
deke Wow somebody did a communicating
with the toyota prius
ho-ho this is exciting all you slack
bros you guys are great um alright
alright we got somewhere to start let me
just make this focus up here ok so we
have this PDF communicating with the
toyota prius decoding the can protocol
[Music]
alright yeah so they're wrong this is
actually only a 500k bus you know
there's also the Charlie Miller paper
and we can learn stuff from they're not
telling me okay okay
alright here we got some numbers so
these numbers are supposed to correspond
to these numbers here it doesn't even
look like we have the same signal so I'm
looking for like the gas pedal position
one or the steering one no no they've
changed it this prius is too new it's
too new so you see these IDs here I'm
searching for them in the data and the
ID by the way is that like number next
to the zero it's - no it's - do you know
what you know where I have a resource
I'm coming I Bounty's see this one
here we go speedometer toyou don't see
if this one matches up today so I put
pages but they don't actually put the
page number so by the way yeah these
graphics were taken from this Toyota T
is thing okay
so this breaking what's fine me let's
start with the easy ones like if the
speed doesn't match up then it's not
gonna be here speedometer Toyota is on
zero B for now I don't have a zero B for
oh yes I do I do have a zero before all
this look sightings okay so they're
claiming that the first they're claiming
that it's gonna oh this is really
exciting I think this matches right so I
just move this over a little bit
knows what I want okay so if this is
correct
we're gonna put this you can see let's
put it over here you have a question
about your fur before using they tell
you question it's okay so these look
like they're all zeros that's true this
is a counter according to the chart
another thing so yeah look it's a
counter now it doesn't look like it
iterates constantly looks like it
aerates based on speed okay it looks
like they didn't maybe do the best job
of reverse engineering themselves but it
I mean it is a counter maybe it's I mean
that's like the odometer itself right so
let's not call it counter let's call it
odometer or maybe maybe the better word
is even encoder you know just like it's
like a shaft encoder this one I agree
with them that it's the checksum oh now
we're finally breaking some stuff open
so yeah just search for it's actually on
our Bounty's page if you want to get
access to this resource as well will I
do this so yeah it's an encoder and it
depends on your speed like that's how
depends how what like the slope of these
lines alright so they're claiming that
this is the speed that's true and maybe
they talk also about where the speed
comes from yes that's the speed look how
well it matches up okay we are getting
somewhere this is very exciting you guys
this is the most exciting part of this
periscope yeah this will even be more
exciting than when we solve four hundred
panelists so what is this okay so this
is man you know I bet you the guys who
wrote this paper wish they had this tool
[Music]
because they did the painful old-school
way all right so do they talk about
where so this is the speedometer speed
so that usually comes from
the transmission and then the wheel
speeds or the packet that goes to the
braking system but okay so the
speedometer is kind of more let's see if
the braking packet matches up so they're
saying it's two eight three look at this
two a three see if it's actually the
same pack
it actually looks like it does nothing
this packet does nothing okay so you
know what they call that they call that
fake news pack it is fake news more
comma points will the raw data know the
raw data is not available to the public
yes I'm still images may be available in
comic colouring that's definitely true
what's the guarantee that comma will be
open I mean never get a guarantee of
anything in a life the incentive well
you get a great dashcam
you earned comma points you're getting
cloud storage for free like to be honest
it's costing us money to store your data
and your training open palette come it's
a company you've a promise that the
driving model will stay public well we
talked a lot about what our I'm reading
off the slack by the way thought I
shouldn't do this on the periscope do
you have a promise the driving model
will stay public we published pretty
openly what our what our model is gonna
be what our monetization and what our
what our plans are as a company okay
so what's interesting is even though
this packet is empty right now
this document is referring to it as the
pre-collision system so let me create
this signal and we'll call it free
collision because even though it doesn't
send anything it might be different from
the adaptive cruise control we may be
able to spoof this packet and hit the
brakes of the car so that is a good
thing to know acceleration acceleration
could be directly linked to a single can
ID so they're talking about this is 37
no now they've lost us we don't have a
37 no 37
ah 266 and this is supposed to be the
steering packets oh yes okay I think
this is how we control steering nearing
control oh okay you know what we're
gonna do
there's actually a place in this video
where we use the intelligent self
parking system all the way at the end so
let's scroll over to that next that out
oh this is this is this is very exciting
oh look what's happening again look it's
it's glitching again I guess I scrolled
way too far
Charlie Miller's paper matches what
we're seeing on our Frias Sonic 392
somebody hand us let's get the 400
all right so let's plot this what are
they claiming these things are flag and
angle nature well yeah they have they
have like a weird biting coating of this
stuff in terms of nipple and minor angle
so actually what this should be is we
can actually remove this signal they're
saying this is the angle so this is
where the self-parking here happens it
looks like that fog is rearing its head
again with some multiple in the graph
393 let's keep it going let's keep it
going okay
let's scroll back to here hopefully the
bug will go away and we can test it over
here
alright let's save this DBC to github
and I'm gonna refresh this page and
we're gonna look seriously into why this
keeps happening you don't actually have
to save the DBC if you refresh it and go
away it's saved in local storage web
browser I have a signals all over the
place
I don't really think they have it right
it might have something to do with
steering but seven more and you could
experience all the joys of reverse
engineering your car like I'm doing
right now so okay that is when I turn
the wheel so it's certainly related to
the steering angle but I think that they
went too far I think maybe it's that
maybe not that all right it's just that
one there oh no I'm dumb I'm dumb look
at what I'm doing guys so you see how
this is a and a n that's actually only
twelve bits I was looking at 24 bits so
that's in the wrong place there right
I'm wrong remove its dude okay this is
our auto endianness detectives just go
in there like that go in there like that
go in there like that oh this is fun
what I love and things just work okay so
that is a flag and that says whether the
intelligent Park Assist system is
enabled and this is an angle claim does
that no that's too much
and then we want this to be a signed
thing because there's a better side
because you can turn this chair a little
both ways all right oh that's a clean
signal take a look at that so that's
gonna be a steering to the left and this
is gonna be a steering to the right I
assume my mother just texted me she said
great press excited I hope you sell 1
million we could we can make a lot of
pandas if we actually sold 1 million I
would I would get on the next flight to
China and we would really have to well
ramp some things up yo you see the Panda
numbers we are at 394 we're right now on
a live stream with the good folks at
periscope reverse engineering the
printer watching that number go up right
so yeah viv owes you $10 I already pay
daddy his $5 hey hey my my moderate
probability chart where I was a market
maker and it was hard for me to lose I
know right
no no I mean it's it's it's it's double
what we predicted yeah so we'll see how
that we'll see how that continues out
yeah yeah the articles have been good
then I've been fans all right cool
so let's see now let's plot this flag
right so this flag never changes but it
should according to this document be set
to 3 when I pass is enabled oh now we're
getting now we're getting all the emails
from the VCS all the VCS only give us
money after they read the articles we
tell the VCS know
that's about that we need to fix too I
mean it's not a huge bug but we should
make the things all look at this all old
guys will you look at this will you look
at this lot of this thing here you see
that three that means we're in I pass
mode Charlie Miller you did a great job
with this reverse engineering thank you
very much for helping us out in creating
this DBC file and watch the cars about
to park itself
and it's about to command to angle and
that is what's gonna let us drive the
Prius around the city so I didn't find
the brake packet but I did with some
great help find the steering control
packet and can i should'a plan to
purchase now hey what if I had it no
these are low tier pcs I mean some of
them are some of them are right but like
you know you don't want you want people
are gonna add value in your company this
is why I always talk about ICO stuff you
know who's gonna add more value to the
crowd I think it's really aligned with
value creation more so than the
traditional VC model which maybe makes a
few people rich we do crowd make a lot
of people rich well don't apply to shark
tank that's that's that's the lowest of
the low if an idea is fun shark tank you
know I mean there's taking money from
the Crown Prince of Dubai and then I
think even below that there's our shark
tank
oh yeah so look at this look at this
this is as the wheel turn so that's the
steering control packet this thing is
amazing
although the smoke right so according to
this documentation although the servo
packet has been reversed the car still
requires the current year to be reverse
oh oh oh this is the current year can I
do okay cool cool oh man these people
are great okay so that's what I called
suspension maybe shows you how much I
know okay it's it's car movement kind of
stuff
data v1v variably used to designate
state of the car state of the petals PD
is car movement gr is gear and counter
okay so I'm wrong that's not a signal
the state of petals let's let's plot
that PE thing car moving it's that here
it's an 8-bit signal and it's signed lot
about this
car movement okay so this is car moving
forward and this is braking or reverse
no I guess that's breaking okay so they
call this car move I'm gonna stop
calling it suspension we're gonna call
it is usually like maybe the body
packets of the car I don't really know
here
[Music]
so that's the car movement and then
these next things are the gear encounter
so this is the gear the car is in this
is counter and this here is the checksum
sure figure I can keep these checks up
soon or start sending these messages
alright so you can see that yeah so they
say three is drive and one is reverse so
we should actually you can set that kind
of stuff at DBC and then one is park so
you can see that I'm in drive here
you're gonna need to plot maybe that no
we're gonna put that let's just pluck
our movement all right so you can see
that I go into reverse here back and
drive for a little bit here and then
with Carson Park right look at this
license to car manufactures license the
car manufacturers is a scam hey maybe
someday I don't want to think about it
really is like a license deal I want to
think about it more like Sirius
satellite radio they include the
hardware with their car and will provide
the software the software is free
I mean it's offers a service so you you
know install the software and then open
pilot has a monthly subscription fee
once it gets really good so we can label
this one here too this thing counts when
moving that doesn't even really seem
like a useful signal I'm not even a
label Ellen oh this is exciting
let's save our newly found information
to my github so by the way this is going
live right now on my github if you go to
github geo hot
you think I have too many embarrassing
private repos they do but yeah you'll
see that this is going right now to
Toyota Prius with the open D BC updates
there you can see the pull requests that
are automatically being created when I
click pull to github and you can see
that this is that a gear package that we
just reverse engineered in the in the
DBC file form so it's pretty cool sweet
let's see what else we have there's
another speed packet okay so this is the
packet responsible for reporting speed
to the system and that does the steering
lock out I already have that one figured
out I just gonna call it speed guess
they already posted it in their paper so
yeah you see that the speed is not
forward or negative it's not positive or
negative it just go negative in Reverse
because of how the wheel encoders work
they're not quadrature colors they're
just normal encoders 398 folks 398 ok so
then they talk about what packets they
said oh then there's also an LK a packet
exciting exciting I don't so you can get
that one this is the steering LK a and
then let's rename the other one oops
I don't want an X naught to be steering
control but we'll call this one steering
intelligent Park Assist system wall
alright so let's do this one quickly see
there's actually a lane five packet I
think should tell us that this guy here
is a counter major angle
carry over I don't know why they
describe it like this just talk about it
like the way DBC is talking about it but
that's an angle this is called LK a
state and this is a check something
alright yeah we're going to move away
from this because that's the intelligent
Park Assist stuff let's see if we can
find where I actually use the lane keep
assist system
let's let's plot the angle right here oh
oh look right there look right there it
does something all right now of course
it's signed so we're gonna have to go in
here and change that to signed yeah okay
all right the bug is back but either way
okay this is where the lane keep assist
system triggers thank you Charlie Miller
you've done a great job and actually
let's think let's really thank the all
this is paper because it's pretty
awesome
as Charlie Miller and Chris Vlasic you
know really some of the early pioneers
in car hacking and they've published
this nice information for us and it is
still relevant today and will be used to
create our Prius DBC on so let's save
our new changes to github and I think
that's mostly what we're gonna show
today so that's how you can start
reverse engineering your car with cabana
data was recorded with a panda you can
go right here to buy pandas I'm sure you
guys have all seen this page because I'm
sure all 61 of you have bought pandas
but if you haven't now is your chance to
make that number go to 400 let's sell
400 panelist so yeah maybe the bug will
go away so I'm gonna sit down with Andy
after this live stream is over and we're
really gonna work on hammering that out
never want to see that happen again
you wanna pan that congratulations
um pants are pretty cool when you win
pans are pretty cool when you buy pan is
pretty cool unlike me in the sunglasses
that's not cool I've heard you loud and
clear YouTube okay cool
so now let's zoom in on this and now
we're gonna see the lane keep assist
system trigger we can go over the
steering packet 399 pandas let's keep it
going one more panda and we can actually
plot the angle here too wow it looks
like this car has a lot of angle sensors
all right so watch watch I'm about to
drift out of the lane and now Lane give
us this triggers to push me back we're
gonna switch up that Lane keep assist
system with open pilot which does a much
much better job I love how simple these
packets are this is super nice thank you
Toyota for making cars that are easy to
hack you guys are gross you are gross is
that what pewdiepie sauce on big PD PI
fans not big enough to know what he says
I've only watched like ten of his videos
but you know PewDiePie is the most
famous youtuber of all time
Wow they show you how to honk the horn
oh this is gonna be great actually even
if someone Wow this is the super useful
stuff yeah yeah crappy OEM Lane keep
assist and that is 400 pandas guys that
is 400 pandas I'm so proud of the Pam
team everything we've done and hopefully
we can all come together as a community
and start creating these DDC files for
cars so I'm gonna do one last commit to
github right here and I think that is
going to be me signing off unless there
are any last questions let me tilt this
back we can take a look
how can panda be used on Tesla yeah it
can um you're not gonna get too much on
the old be deport like there's an
instructable that shows you the right
place to wire it in and that for the
Dubai Crown Prince I shouldn't say
anything bad about the Dubai Crown
Prince I mean is the conference in Dubai
I'm just saying like you know there's
who you want to take money from as a
company and uh you know like what top
tier VCS and I think you know I like I
said I'm a big fan of I CEOs I think
that's a great way forward um we're
actually at 4:01 pandas that's too many
pandas we're gonna stop the video 400
laughs now you just need to get a car
that is supported yeah I mean you know
the pan of stuff is entirely open as
well
does Tesla have similar tools internally
I bet they're nowhere near as good as
this to be honest I bet they're nowhere
near as good upcoming giveaway pandas we
have a bunch more rev B's to giveaway
but yeah eventually they're gonna be Rev
sees as well so there are still panda
giveaways organized by our
administrators on the forums I'll give
away a couple pandas every week what car
works the best with open pilot right now
the 2016 Honda Civic that was last
year's flagship model but we've
announced that this year's flagship
model is gonna be the 2017 Toyota Prius
so if you want the car for the future
get that one if you want come on the
Civic is a pretty good experience it's
not gonna be quite as good as Tesla
autopilot it helps a lot the Tesla's
deeply you know Tesla made the car but
actually a lot of that we can fix we can
fix with software so pretty good
experience in the Civic good experience
in the Civic better in the ILX
but you know this year's flagship Toyota
Prius ah the Accord I wrote half accord
support and then I got bored somebody
can finish it especially now that I just
really wanted to make sure that the
Panda hard work and support the Accord
and I can tell you that again because
I've seen everything get done get
triggered it's just a question of wire
hair all up and making it nice and if
you did this this $2,000 for you can you
order Khamenei I oh the swag items no I
extended I was nice I extended it from
100 to 200 do I plan to celebrate no I
plan to hack my Priya
I'm gonna go do live stream again once
we actually have the wheel turning
but yeah cool well thanks for tuning in
guys that was reverse engineering of the
Prius bye-bye
oh I swipe down okay